"Vikings".. 기미갤 와그그그.
Last season on "Vikings"...
신들은 너가 위대한 미래를 가지는걸 바라고 있어.
The gods desire you
to have a great future.
그가 새로운 항해길을 찻았습니다.
He's found a new way
to navigate the sea.
큰 마을과 도시 그리고 보물들,
Great towns, and cities,
and treasures,
그리고 새로운 신.
and a new God.
- 왜 이자식을 죽이지 않았어?
- 내가 죽이지 말라그랬어.
- Why have you not killed this one?
- I forbid it.
너가 어떻게 죽이지 말라고
할수있는거지?, 우리는 동등하잖아.
How can you forbid it,
little brother, we are equals.
너도 이해하다 싶이 이 보물들은 나의 것이야.
You understand
that all this belongs to me.
나의 꿈속에서, 우리는 언제나 함께였어.
In my dreams,
we are always together.
- 남자가 하는일이 뭐지?
- 그는 가족들을 돌봅니다.
- What does a man do?
- He look after his family.
- 그리고?
- 싸웁니다.
- And?
- He fights.
라그나 백작님을 위해 만세!
Hail, Earl Ragnar!
라그나 백작님 만세!
언제쯤 우리가 동등해질까,
나의 형제여?
How will we ever be equal now,
my brother?
우리는 서쪽으로 가기위한 많은 배들이 필요 할 것이다,
We shall have more ships to go West,
그것이 우리의 미래다.
for that is our future.
왜 신들은 나를 백작으로 만들고,
나의 아들을 죽였을까?
Why did the gods make me Earl,
yet kill my son?
- 우리는 다시 아들을 가질 수 있어.
- 우리가 시도 안했었나?
- We can have more sons.
- Have we not tried?
Ragnar Lothbrok!
호릭왕님, 제가 어떻게 힘이 될 수 있을가요?
King Horik, how can I be of help?
고틀랜드에 귀족이 하나 있어,
보그 자식....
There is a Jarl in Gotaland,
Jarl Borg.
그가 나를 위협하고 있어.
He threatens me.
너가 호릭왕으로 부터 온 사자냐?
Are you the emissaries
from King Horik?
넌 시간낭비 하고 있는거야.
You're wasting your time.
여기는 나의 땅이고
그리고 나는 나에게 돌아온 이 땅을 원해 .
It's my land
and I want it returned to me.
호릭왕은 당신의 주장을 거절 했습니다.
King Horik resists your claim.
안되!
No!
난 아마 죽을거야.
I am going to die.
넌 죽지않아.
신들이 원하는게 무엇인가요?
You are not going to die.
What is it that the gods want?
너에게서 무언가를 가져가는거.
To take something from you.
나는 아슐라그 공주입니다,
I am Princess Aslaug,
저희 어머니는 여전사 본헬가 였습니다 .
my mother was
the shield-maiden Brunhilde.
Shall I tell Lagertha, your wife?
만약 당신이 정말 위대한 남자가 되고싶다면,
If you really want to be a great man,
당신은 저가 필요합니다. 제가 당신을 필요로 하는것 만큼.
you need me
as much as I need you.
너가 정말로 원하는게 뭔데?
What is it you really want?
너의 형제의 죽음 그리고 너 자신의 명성을 위한 출발?
The death of your brother
and the start of your own fame?
제가 당신의 아이를 잉태하고 있습니다.
I'm carrying your child.
나의 형제에 대적하여 너와 함께 싸울게.
I will fight with you
against my bother.
__
아직 내 형제로 부터 어떤 얘기도 듣지 못했어,
I've had no message
from my brother,
하지만 내마음은 여전히 그가 나를 배신하지 않을거라고 믿고있어.
but I still believe in my heart
that he will not betray me,
그는 나를 배반할 이유가 없거든.
for he has no reason.
누가 배신하는데 이유가 필요하나?
Who needs a reason for betrayal?
항상 최악의 경우를 생각해야되, 라그나,
One must always think
the worst, Ragnar,
설령 그가 너의 혈족이라도.
even of your own kin.
그래야만, 너의 인생에 있어서 많은 좌절을 피할 수 있거든.
That way, you avoid too much
disappointment in life.
저기 배신자 녀석이 있구만.
There is the treacherous one.
내 말이 옳았지 라그나.
I was right, Ragnar.
내 말이 맞았어.
I was right.
Sync and corrected by Elderfel
www.addic7ed.com
♪ More, give me more ♪
♪ Give me more ♪
♪ If I had a heart
I could love you ♪
♪ If I had a voice I would sing ♪
♪ After the night when I wake up ♪
♪ I'll see what tomorrow brings ♪
♪ I... I... I... ♪
♪ If I had a voice I would sing ♪
적의 사자가 다가옵니다!
Rider approaching!
원하는게 뭐야?
What is it you want?
라그나 로스브로크를 대신하여 여기 왔습니다.
I'm here on behalf
of Ragnar Lothbrok.
그의 형제와 이야기 하고싶습니다.
I want to speak to his brother.
이야기 해봐.
Then speak.
롤로,
Rollo,
너는 나와 많은 전쟁을 함께 해왔지.
you and I fought together many times.
너가 잊어 버렸을 거라고 생각하지 않아.
I don't suppose you've forgotten.
난 너를 형제라고 생각하고 있거든...
I think of you as a brother...
그러나 저쪽에 너의 진짜 형제가 있지,
but over there is your real brother,
너의 진정한 혈육.
your own flesh and blood.
정말 그에 대적하여 도끼를 들어 올리고 싶어?
Are you sure you want to raise
your axe against him?
라그나가 널 보냈냐?
Did Ragnar send you?
라그나에게 어떤 대답을 전해줘야하지?
What answer shall I give him?
그에게 전해 피와 함께 대답할 거라고
Tell him I shall answer him
with blood.
방패의 벽! (바이킹이 자주 쓰던 전법)
Shield-wall!
방패의 벽!
창병!
Spears!
돌격!
Charge!
대형 유지해!
Hold the wall!
너의 죽음이 코 앞이다!
Your death is on its way!
플로키!
Floki!
이게 너가 진짜 원하던 거야, 형제여?
Is this what you really want,
brother?
난 너와 싸울 수 없어.
I cannot fight you.
패배 당하지 않았지만,
Without being defeated,
우리의 젋은이들이 서로 죽이는거에 점점 지쳐가고 있어.
we have grown weary
of the slaughter of our young men.
그래서... 보그
So, Jarl Borg,
너에게 제안하겠네...
I offer you...
분쟁영토에서 3분의 1을 너에게 주겠네.
one third of the profits
from the disputed lands.
너가 더 이상 나의 의견에 논쟁을 일으키지 않는다면.
Unless you continue
to dispute my claim to it.
전 차라리 다시 싸울겁니다 그리고 합당하지 않은 정의를 받겠죠 .
I would rather go back fighting,
than receive such scant justice.
그러니깐, 자네는 나의 공정한 제안을 거절하겠다는 건가?
So, you'll not accept my fair offer?
거절하겠습니다.
No.
왜 계속 자국내를 보고 있는거지?
Why do we continue looking inwards?
왜?!!
Why?!
왜 우리는 서로 싸우냐고
Why do we fight each other
이 좆만한 땅 때문에 또는 저기 좆만한 땅 때문에
about this piece or that piece of land?
왜 바깥 세상을 쳐다보지 않는거냐고? 서쪽으로?
Why are we not looking outwards
to the West?
만약 우리가 함께 습격한다면,
If we raided together,
우리는 우리끼리 싸울 필요가 없을거야.
we would not need to fight
amongst ourselves.
더 이상 우리 젋은이들이 서로 죽일 필요가 없을거라고.
We would not need to kill
anymore of our young folk.
서로 죽이는 대신,
But instead,
땅을 제공하자고,
offer them land,
그들이 농사 지을 수 있는 땅을.
land that they can farm.
He speaks the truth.
나의 마음은 라그나와 같네.
My mind tends the same way
as Ragnar's.
그와 함께 참여하는게 나의 목적일세
It is my intention to join with him
그리고 서쪽을 항해하는거지.
and sail West.
자네 의견은 뭔가, 보그?
What do you say, Jarl Borg?
좋습니다,
Yes,
자네와 함께 습격하지,
I will raid with you,
그리고 당신의 제안을 수락하겠습니다.
and so I accept your offer.
너의 걱정은 하지마, 형제여,
Not that you'd care, brother,
그러나 너의 조카 기다는 죽었어.
but your niece, Gyda, is dead.
집으로 돌아갈 시간이야.
Time to go home.
플로키! 플로키!
Floki! Floki!
죽지마.. 제발 죽지마..
Don't die. Please don't die.
What's happened to them?!
애꾸는 죽었어.
One Eye died.
아너요?!
Arne?!
롤로 자식이 죽여버렸어.
Rollo killed him.
그리고 플로키는 심한 부상으로 살아남기 힘들거야.
And Floki may not survive
for he is so badly wounded.
이 사건은 당신의 싸움이 아니였어.
This was not your quarrel.
이 사건에 연루되지 않았어야 됬어.
You should not have become involved.
무슨 일이 일어났는지를 봐봐!
Look what has happened!
이러한 일들을 겪지 않고서는
No man can walk through life
누구든 세상을 살아갈 수 없어, 라그리타.
without things happening
to him, Lagertha.
당신이 선택한 거 잖아.
You chose.
그래, 내가 선택했지, 그리고 롤로도 선택했어.
Yes. I chose, and Rollo chose.
그리고 롤로의 선택은 이러한 결과를 이끌었지!
And Rollo's choice led to all this!
두분다 그만 다투세요.
Don't argue you two.
피곤하고 이제 구역질나,
I am weary and I'm blood-sickened,
그리고 그게 진실이야.
and that is the truth.
아슐라그가 누구야?
Who is Aslaug?
그만해.
Stop.
아슐라그가 누구냐고?
Who is Aslaug?
요틀랜드의 공주야
She's a Gotaland princess.
요틀랜드에서 만났어.
We met her over there.
단지 그냥 만났다고?
You just met her?
라그리타.
Lagertha.
아들이 뭐라고 말했는데?
What has the boy told you?
라그리타에게 뭐라고 말했니?
What did you tell her, boy?
비욘이 말한건 상관할게 아니야.
It doesn't matter what Bjorn says.
넌 뭐라고 말할건데?
What do you say?
난.....
I say...
남들앞에서 더러운 옷을 빨면 안되지.
we should not wash our dirty clothes
in front of others.
그년과 잤어?
Did you have sex with her?
어, 잤어.
Yes, I had sex with her.
몇번이나??
How many times?!
한번.
Once.
그녀를 사랑하는게 아니야.
I don't love her.
내가 어떻게 널 떠나보내겠어?
How can I make you let this go?
다신 그년 보지마.
Never see her again.
알았어.
Done.
다시는 보지마.
Never again.
왜 엄마와 이러한 다툼들이 있는거죠?
Why are there such problems
between you?
왜 그런지 알잖니.
You know why.
그러나 엄마와 아빠 사이에 다툼이 있는건 싫어요.
But I don't want there
to be problems.
그냥 아버지가 한 일에 대해 미안하다고 하면 안되는건가요?
Can't you just say sorry
for what you've done?
그건 너의 엄마와는 쉬운일이 아니란다.
It's not so easy
with your mother.
그리고 롤로에게는 어떤 처벌이 일어나나요?
And what will happen to Rollo?
난 나의 형제를 판결할 수 없어.
I cannot judge my own brother.
우리는 모임이 있을거고 입법자가 판결하겠지.
We will have an assembly
and the Law-Giver will judge.
우리는 롤로를 판결의 바위 위에 시험할거야.
We will take Rollo
up to the Law Rock
그리고, 그 바위가 그의 운명이 결정될 장소지.
and that is where his fate
will be decided.
가지고 계신것이 뭐에여?
What's that you have?
잉글랜드에서 가져온 황금동전.
A gold coin. From England.
보이니?
You see?
심지어 동전에 에일리왕 얼굴도 있단다.
It even has King Aelle's
face upon it.
그러니깐, 이거 비싼건가요?
So it's worth a fortune?
원하는게 뭡니까?
What do you want?
그와 말하고 싶어요.
To talk to him.
롤로....
Rollo...
롤로...저에요
Rollo, it's me.
방해하지마.
Don't bother.
죽은 사람을 감싸줄 수 없어..
You cannot warm up a dead man.
저새끼는 불명예로는 새끼야.
He is without honor!
- Kill him!
- I spit on you!
반역자새끼! 반역자새끼!
Traitor! Traitor!
Now he'll pay for what he's done!
죽여버려! 반역자새끼!
- Kill him!
- Traitor! Traitor!
Kill him!
Shame on you!
여러분, 당신들의 입법자로써,
People, as your Law-Giver,
이 남자의 운명을 결정하기위해 물음 받아왔습니다.
I have been asked to determine
the fate of this man.
이 남자는 우리의 적의 편에 서서 싸우고
This man chose to fight
with our enemies.
그의 형제에 대적해서 싸웠습니다.
Chose to fight against his brother.
반역자!
Traitor!
이 자는 많은 우리들의 아들들을 죽였습니다.
He killed many of our sons,
형제들.. 아버지들..
brothers, fathers.
어떠한 희망이 그에게 있겠습니까?
What hope is there for him?
그는 변명의 여지가 없습니다.
He has no defense!
이 남자는 죽어도 합당합니다.
This man deserves to die.
Yeah!
우리 모두 그건 압니다.
We all know that.
하지만.... 난 이 자를 살리기로 결정했습니다.
But... I have decided to spare him.
저는 신들로 부터 조언을 받았습니다.
I have taken the advice of the gods.
만약 신들이 그가 죽기를 바랬더라면,
If they had wanted him dead,
그는 전장에서 죽었어야 했습니다.
he would have died in battle.
그리나 신들은 그를 살렸습니다.
But they spared him.
그는 앞으로 나와
He came forward
그의 형제의 자비에 애원했습니다.
and threw himself
upon the mercy of his brother.
그는 흥미롭고, 예상치 못했던 행동을 했습니다.
He behaved in an interesting
and unexpected way,
그러므로 나는 결정내렸습니다.
and therefore, I conclude...
이것은 신들이 만든 판결이라고.....
that the gods have made
their own judgment,
제가 어떻게 할 수 없는...
which I cannot overturn.
그러므로 저는 이 남자는 자유롭게 풀려난다고 명령합니다.
I therefore order
this man be set free.
반역자를 죽여!
Kill the traitor!
어찌됫든, 우리는 저새끼를 죽여야되! 너가 족장이잖아.
We should kill him anyway.
You are the Earl!
안되. 우리는 법을 따라야만되.
No. We must obey the law.
저새끼가 법을 내린다고?? 단지 평범한 사람일뿐이야
Who is the Law-Giver?
Just an ordinary man.
그가 신성한 돌위에 있을때는 평범한 사람이아니야.
Not when he stands
on the Sacred Stone.
나는 너의 그림자로부터 벗어나고 싶었었어.
I wanted to step out of your shadow.
이해하지?
You understand, don't you?
하지만 내가 너의 그림자로부터 벗어났을때.... 거기에는 빛이 없었어,
But when I stepped out of it,
there was... there was no sunlight,
작은 어떠한 빛도.
no sunlight at all.
뭐하는거야?
What are you doing?
떠나려고.
Leaving.
여기 모두들 나를 증오해. 합당한 이유들이야.
Everyone hates me here...
with good reason.
나는 그들을 배신했었어.
I have betrayed them.
더이상 이 곳에 머물 이유가 없어.
There is no point in my staying.
하지만 나에게 심지어 아무말 없이 떠나려고 했나요?
But you are going to leave
and not even say goodbye to me?
그렇게 하는게 너한테 편할 줄 알았어.
I thought you would
prefer it that way.
나에 대해서 조금이라도 알고있나요?
Do you really know me so little?
난 너에게 줄게 아무것도 없어.
I have nothing to offer you.
당신과 모두를 위해서 좋았을거야.
It would have been better
for you, for me, for everyone
만약, 내가 처형되었더라면.
if I had been executed.
그러면 당신을 지금 신들을 무시하는 건가요?
So you take no account of the gods?
신들이 당신에게 준 것에 대해 무엇이라고 말할래요?
What would you say
the gods have offered you?
남은 일생을 쪽팔리게 사는거.
A lifetime of humiliation.
아니에요! 그게 아니에요!
No! That is not it!
신들은 당신에게 다시 태어날 기회를 주었어요,
The gods have offered you
a chance to be reborn,
구원되기 위해서, 발할라에 가기 위해서.
to be redeemed, to gain Valhalla.
이 뜻들이 신들이 당신에게 준 것이에요.
That is what they have offered you.
하지만, 당신은 도망칠려고 하는군요.
But you, you want to run away.
당신은 쥐구멍에 숨으려고 하고있어요.
You want to hide in a hole
somewhere.
내가 어디에 갈 수 있는데?
Where else can I go?
왜 어디론가 가야 하죠?
Why do you have to go anywhere?
기다,
Gyda,
너에게 제대로된 작별인사를 하러 왔어.
I have come to say goodbye
to you properly.
너가 어렸을때부터 너를 생각해왔어.
I have been thinking about you,
about when you were small.
넌 매우 활발했었지,
You were so lively,
넌 마치 바람처럼 빠르게 달릴 수 있었지.
you could run as swiftly
as the wind.
너는 예상할 수 없는 아이였어.
You were like quick-silver.
근데, 내가 이걸 다 알기전에,
But then, before I knew it,
넌 달리는걸 멈춰버렸어.
you stopped running
here and there and everywhere
그리고 넌 항상....
and you became still.
12살에 아이야.
At 12-years-old,
너는 좋은 여성이 되기위한 침착함과 고요함을 가지고 있었어.
you had the stillness
and the calm of a fine woman.
너가 낳은 아이들은 어땠을까!
What children
you would have produced!
너가 어떤 행복을 우리에게 가져다 줬을수 있었을까.
What joy that would have
brought to all of us.
나의 아이, 기다에게,
Dear child, Gyda,
넌 사라지는게 아니야 왜냐면 넌 항상 나의 마음에 존재 할거거든.
you are not gone because
you are always in my heart.
사람들은 말해 남자는 아들을 더 사랑해야 한다고,
They say that a man must love
his sons more,
하지만, 남자는 아들을 시기할 수 있어,
but a man can be jealous
of his sons,
그리고 딸은 항상 그의 인생에 빛이 되어주지.
and his daughter can always be
the light in his life.
너가 신들과 함께 있다는걸 알고있어,
I know very well
that you are with the gods,
아빠는 여기에 잠시만 머물러 있을게,
but I will wait here awhile,
그리고 너가 와서 아빠와 얘기하고 싶으면,
and if you want to come
and talk to me,
와서 얘기해,
then come and talk,
그러면 너의 아름답고 긴 머리를 다시 한번 어루만질게
and I will gently stroke
your long and beautiful hair once again
나의 거친손으로...
with my peasant hands.
아빠!
Father!
- 뭔일이야?
- 저기 뭔가가 오고있어요.
- What?
- There's someone coming.
Keep steady! Take the oars!
Pull in the ropes!
나를믿어, 나도 뭔일인지 모르겠어.
You must believe me,
I had no idea.
내가 오라고 하지 않았어.
I did not ask her to come.
비욘이 나에게 말해줬어요.
Bjorn told me that your mother
당신의 어머니가 여전사 본헬다 였다고.
was the shield-maiden, Brunhilde,
저희가 모두 들은 그분 맞나요?
of whom we've all heard?
사실입니다.
It's true.
어머니가 제가 어릴쩍 일찍 돌아가시긴 했지만요.
Although she died
when I was very young.
그럼 부친은??
And your father?
저의 부친은 시가드 입니다.
My father was Sigurd.
시가드..?
Sigurd...?
시가드요...?
Just Sigurd?
아니요, 제 말은...
No, I mean the Sigurd
서사시에 따르면 파브니르의 용을 죽인 시가드요.
who, according to the sagas,
killed the dragon Fafnir.
그럼 부친께서도 영웅이시네요.
Then your father is also a hero.
사람들이 그에 대해 말하는것은 사실입니다.
그리고 저는 그분이 저의 부친이신게 자랑스럽죠.
People talk about him, it's true,
and I'm proud that he was my father.
하지만, 전 그를 만나본 적이 없어요.
But I never knew him.
당신에 부모님들은 어떤분들 이셨나요?
What about your parents?
흠....
Hmm.
두분 모두 그냥 농부셨어요.
They were just farmers.
누구도 "그냥" 농부는 없어요.
Surely nobody is just a farmer.
믿어주세요, 공주님,
Believe me, princess,
농부는 정확히 몇몇 사람들이 하는일이고, 그들은 행복해 한답니다.
that is exactly what some people are,
and are happy to be.
죄송했습니다.
Forgive me.
날 기억하니 비욘?
Do you remember me, Bjorn?
우리가 생명의 나무앞에 서있었던걸 기억하니?
Do you remember we stood
in front of the Tree of Life?
그건 생명의 나무가 아니였어요, 그냥 나무 였죠.
It wasn't Yggdrasil.
It was just a tree.
너가 맞아. 우리 둘다 그 사실을 알고있잖니.
You're right.
We both know that.
이러한 일들은 우리사이에 유대를 만든단다.
It creates a bond between us.
전 그렇게 생각하지 않아요.
I don't think so.
우리는 어떠한 유대도 없어요.
We don't have any bond.
전 공주님과 어떠한 유대도 공유하고 싶지 않아요.
I don't want any bond with you.
왜 저 여자에게 빨리 떠나라고 말하지 않는거죠?
Why don't you just tell her
that she has to leave soon?
저 여자는 여기에 머물수 없어요.
She can't stay here.
공주는 내 아이를 임신했어.
She is carrying my child.
저 여자때문에 불편해지고 행복하지 않아요.
She brings unhappiness
and difficulty.
아버지는 장님이에요? 아버지는 이게 안보여여?
Can't you see that? Are you blind?
나도 안다. 너에게는 받아 들이기 힘들겠지.
I know it is hard for you
to accept,
그러나 불행함은 행복함보다 훨씬 일반적 이란다.
but unhappiness
is more common than happiness.
누가 너에게 넌 행복해야 된다고 했니?
Who told you
you should be happy?
너도 이제 성숙해져야할 나이가 되었단다.
You've come to an age
where you must be grow up
그리고 이러한일들에 책임감을 가져야지.
and be responsible
about such things.
내가 너만 했을때, 아빠는 많은 친구들이 있었단다.
When I was your age,
I had many friends.
하지만, 모두들 죽었지.
All are dead.
행복은 여기에도 없고 어디에도 없단다.
The happiness is
neither here nor there.
그 여자에 대해 얼마나 알고있어?
How much do you know
about this woman?
그냥 비욘이 말해 준 정도, 많이 몰라.
Only what Bjorn told me,
which was not much.
자기 아버지에게 불효자가 되고싶지 않나봐.
He did not wish to be disloyal
to his father.
저 여자가 라그나의 아이를 임신한 사실은 전혀 알고 있지 못했었어.
I did not know
she was carrying his child, though.
라그나의 아이라는걸 믿어?
And you believe it?
라그나는 믿고 있어.
Ragnar believes it.
그럼 저 여자네 부모님 얘기는?
What of all her stories
of Brunhilde and Sigurd?
사실이겠지 뭐.
I suppose so.
확실히 그녀는 우리와는 다르잖아.
She is clearly different from us.
그래서 어찌 할건데?
What are you going to do?
나도 몰라.
I don't know.
나의 아들을 위해 옳은 일을 해야지.
I must do what is right for my son.
오, 플로키!
Oh, Floki!
아직 죽지 않았단다, 비욘
I'm not dead yet, Bjorn.
넌 됬어, 라그나.
No thanks to you, Ragnar.
그래, 니가 나에게 맘에 드는점이 있나 말해봐,
Oh. Say what you'd like about me,
난 그냥 신들이 널 살려둘 만큼 멍청하다는 사실이 기쁘다.
I'm just glad that the gods
were stupid enough to save you.
신들...그리고 헬가.
The gods... and Helga.
어서 힘을 회복해야되.
You must regain your strength.
많은 할 일들이 있잖아.
배 많이 만들어야지.
There's much to do.
A whole fleet of boats to be built.
너랑 나는 아직 아무것도 못 본거야.
우리의 여행은 이제 막 시작됬다고.
You and I have seen nothing yet.
Our journeys have just begun.
그래 너 말이 맞아.
It's true!
난 내가 죽은줄로만 알았어.
I thought I was dead
그리고 내가 죽었다고 생각했었을때,
다른 곳에 대한 꿈을 꿧어.
and while I was dead,
I was dreaming of other places,
너랑 내가 항해 해야할 장소 말이야.
the places that you and I
shall sail to, Ragnar.
쉬어.
Rest.
가자, 애야.
Come on, boy.
-플로키!
-이봐, 플로키!
- Floki!
- Hey, Floki!
- 그래, 비욘.
- 플로키!
- Hello, Bjorn.
- Floki!
당신이 받아 줬으면 해요, 제가 선택한 것들과
I hope you will accept
what I have chosen
그리고 제가 당신을 위해 준비한것들을
and prepared for you?
Generous!
당신이 이러한 곤란들을 가져올거 라고 생각 못 했네요.
I did not expect you to go
to so much trouble.
이건 곤란함이 아니죠, 제가 가져온것들이 당신을 기쁘게 만든다면요.
It is no trouble,
if it is pleasing to you.
진실을 말해봐요,
To tell you the truth,
그쪽이 요리할 수 있다는걸 상상하지 못했네요.
I did not imagine you could cook!
저 요리 못해요. 제 시녀들이 요리 했죠.
I can't. My women cooked,
전 그냥 재료들을 가져다 주었구요.
I just bought the ingredients.
내 집에서 당신 둘을 보고 있자니...
Looking at both of you here,
in my home...
왜 당신들이 함께 지내는게 안되는지 모르겠군.
I see no reason why you two
should not get on together.
당신둘은 너무 달라 하지만 둘다 강인해.
You two are very different,
yet both strong.
비슷한 협정들을 내가 들었었는데
I have heard that
similar arrangements exist
많은 나라에서 존재해.
all over this country.
뭔 협정 말하는건데??
What arrangements?
백작은 여러명의 여자와 살 수 있어.
That an Earl can live
with more than one woman.
사실, 일반적인 것은 아니야.
In fact, it is not unusual.
근데 모두에게 이익이 될거야.
It works to the benefit of everyone,
특히 아이들한테.
especially the children.
물론, 둘다 결혼하는거지.
Of both marriages, of course.
사실이에요. 저도 많은 사례들을 알아요.
It's true.
I know of many such instances.
맞아.
Yes.
이게 당신이 나한테 제안하는 거야??
Is that what you're suggesting?
그렇다고 하면,
If I were,
뭐라고 할건데?
what would you say?
미안해, 근데 그 여자는 내아이를 임신하고 있어.
I'm sorry, but this woman
is carrying my child.
나는 그녀를 돌봐야하고, 당신도 받아 들어야만 해.
I must take care of her.
You must accept.
우리 아이를 유산했을때, 너무 가슴이 아팟어.
When we lost our unborn son,
it broke my heart.
아이를 지키지 못했고, 다시는 이러지 않을거야.
I had failed
and I will not fail again.
그냥 그녀를 그렇게 모른척 할 수 없어.
I cannot turn this woman away.
내 아이를 돌봐야지.
I have to take care of my child.
도끼 챙기는거 잊지마.
Don't forget the axe.
떠나는 거야?
You are leaving then?
당연히 떠나야죠.
Of course I'm leaving.
비욘도 당신과 함께 가나요?
Is Bjorn going with you?
그건 비욘에게 달렸어요.
That's up to Bjorn.
비욘, 넌 지금 중대한 선택을 해야되.
Bjorn,
you have a big choice to make.
나는 너의 어머니를 존경한단다. 모두들 그래.
I admire your mother.
We all do.
그러나 넌 너의 아버지와 함께 지내야되.
But you have to stay
with your father.
만약 너가 안그런다면, 넌 살면서 평생 후회할거야.
If you don't, you will regret it
for the rest of your life.
잊지마 너의 아버지는, 라그나 로스브로크 라는걸.
Remember, your father
is Ragnar Lothbrok.
비욘
Bjorn.
선택해야되.
You have to choose.
말해봐.
Say it now.
난...난 아버지와 함께 지낼게요.
I... I choose my father.
좋아.
Very well.
뭐일이야?
What?
엄마가 떠났어요.
Mother's left.
Move!
당신, 한마디도 없이 꼭 이렇게 날 두고 떠나야겠어?
You're really going to abandon me
without even saying a word?
당신은 나에게 수치심과 모욕감을 줬어.
You insult and humiliate me.
당신을 떠나는것 밖에는 선택의 여지가 없어.
I have no choice but to leave you
그리고 당신과 이혼하는거.
and divorce you.
당신이 떠나는걸 원하지 않아.
I don't want you to go.
이게 운명이야.
It's fate.
마음이 바꿨어요. 엄마와 함께 갈게요.
I've changed my mind.
I'm coming with you.
엄마를 잘 보살피거라.
Look after your mother.
이리오렴.
Come on.
가자.
Move on.
첫번째로 만든 자막입니다.. 의역많고 어색한것도 많은데 봐주셔서 감사합니다~
꾸벅~ 즐거운 하루 되세요
Sync and corrected by Elderfel
www.addic7ed.com